You have to think about what
you're putting behind your strikes.
That's what's gonna tip
things in your favor.
What do you mean? It's like,
for Volo,
it's the pride and
responsibility that comes with
being from a family that
teaches swordsmanship.
For Golgorosso, it's the confidence
he's got from having muscles of steel.
And for Lina, it's the pride she
takes in her polished skills.
That's the reason why their attacks
are as powerful as they are.
Then what do you think I
should put behind my sword?
That's something you're gonna
have to figure out yourself.
I'm not a noble or swordsman.
All I have are my years spent
in a forest wielding an axe.
That and the Aincrad
style Kirito taught me.
Wait, I have something else.
the dark and the dark.
The first thing that you
could see is the only one.
You can't even use it.
I won't be able to do it.
I'm ready.
I'm ready. I'm ready.
I'm ready to continue.
I'm ready. I'm ready to go.
I'm ready.
I'm ready to go.
Shining sun, my diamond?
It's a dream of a dream!
It seems Disciple Eugeo
prefers hacking away at logs,
rather than working on his form.
I recall once hearing Sir Eugeo used to
be a woodcutter in some backwoods hovel.
Perhaps the extent of his knowledge is
limited to methods of attacking lumber.
How truly unfortunate.
If that is indeed the case, then as someone
who happens to train in the same dorm,
perhaps I should graciously lend a hand
and instruct him on proper technique.
My, what a considerate thing
of you to offer, Lord Rios.
You truly are an exemplary noble.
What say you to that, Sir Eugeo?
Will you accept Lord Raios'
generosity and have him train you?
It's a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
I appreciate the offer.
Some upperclassmen use their
status as a source of power.
Is that why first-seat Raios and
second-seat Umber are so strong?
It's a little different with those guys.
Their egos are on a whole nother level.
Why do you think that is?
Because they're a couple of jerks.
Hell, they've been looking down their noses
at people since the day they were born.
They sure don't think much of us.
For one, we're from outside the capital.
Plus, we don't have any
kind of noble heritage.
This might be a good opportunity for me to
find out just what their
egos are capable of.
Forgive me for misspeaking just now.
I would happily accept a lesson from you.
Oh, he can't be serious. I am.
In fact,
I would like my lesson in
the form of a match with you,
Sir Oombear, if that
isn't too much trouble.
Why, you rotten...
May I remind you that Lord Oombear is
no slouch when it comes to swordplay.
He may end up striking you.
I would prefer if he
stopped just short of that.
But if he hits me, then I must accept it.
This lesson is for my benefit, after all.
Very well.
I will be more than happy to demonstrate
my skills for you, Sir Eugeo.
Let us begin, then.
Prepare to bear witness to the
essence of the High Norkian Style!
Lightning Slash!
The Norkian Style's secret move!
En Kirito!
Huh.
If it's a case of who's stronger, I am!
Don't get cocky, you commoner!
His power surged.
Is that what his arrogance is capable of?
Your sword style is a good match
for you, primitive and unsightly.
Let's see how you fare
after I crush your shoulder.
I have to switch skills.
That is enough.
I declare this match a draw.
But, Lord Raios, I can't walk
away from this rogue with a draw.
I must finish this.
Stand down, Umber.
For what it's worth, Disciple Yu-Gi-Oh,
your outlandish moves
were quite entertaining.
After graduating,
perhaps you should consider seeking
a calling with the Imperial Circus.
Thank you for the
suggestion, Disciple Raios.
In due time, I will give you my own
demonstration of a nobleman's power.
I'm free now, if you are.
There is more to battle than waving
a sword around, you nameless buffoon.
It's been three days.
They should have tried
getting back at me by now.
I wonder why they haven't.
They'd be breaking the rules.
The schools and the taboo indexes.
Those don't make it easy to harass people.
On the other hand, anything that doesn't
fall under the rules is up for debate.
They could be looking for a loophole.
You think they go that far?
Just to spite me?
I don't know.
Maybe they're not planning
on doing anything.
It's possible they're just
trying to psych you out.
Whatever you do, don't let it get to you.
No matter what, you gotta stay cool.
What did you say?
Stay what now?
Oh, uh, that's the secret
mantra of the Aincrad style.
It's pretty much the
same as saying stay calm.
You can also use it to
say goodbye to someone.
It's like another way
of saying see you later.
Oh, okay.
I'll remember that. Stay cool.
What an unusual thing to say. Stay cool?
Bizarre.
All right, I'm gonna go hit the sack.
Oh, hey, by the way, about tomorrow?
I have to run some
errands so you're on here.
I know you don't.
We promised Tiese and Ronier
we'd take them out for a picnic.
And by we, I mean us.
So if you think you can get
out of it, you're mistaken.
They'll be here at 9 sharp.
So make sure you're
ready to leave by then.
You got it?
Okay, okay.
Do me a favor, though,
and wake me up at 8.
I need to catch up on some sleep.
No, 8 o 'clock's way too late.
Make it 7.30.
And stay cool.
I know I told you that
phrase is like saying bye,
but it's not something you
say to someone going to bed.
Why not?
Because you don't.
You use it when you're really
saying goodbye to someone.
Oh, what a complicated phrase.
If what Kirito said is true,
are Umber and Raios capable of
sidestepping the laws of the Axiom Church?
What am I saying?
You can't even doubt the Taboo
Index much less disobey it?
If there were a way around it,
I could have done something,
instead of stand there and
watch Alice get taken away.
Why couldn't I disobey
when I had the chance?
Alice.
Eugeo, are you listening?
Yujiyo?
Huh?
Sorry, I missed that last part.
You were saying?
You didn't hear a single word.
I'm sorry, I just...
I was just admiring how
beautiful the forest was.
It has animals I've never seen before.
Really?
Yeah, like that one.
Oh, that?
That's just a plain old golden flying fox.
Don't tell me you've never seen one.
They're in every tree in the capital.
Oh, right.
I guess you'd be used to them since
you were born and raised here.
That's true.
Do your folks live nearby?
No, they live in District 8.
It's a bit of a ways away
from where we are in 5.
Oh, you don't say.
Hang on.
If I'm not mistaken, don't you
come from a family of nobles?
I thought all of the mansions
were in Districts 3 and 4.
Only nobles who are fourth-ranked or
higher get to live in that district.
My father is a sixth-ranked nobleman,
therefore he has no judicial authority.
I didn't know that.
I thought that was
something every noble has.
Certainly not!
Only nobles fourth rank or
higher are granted that power,
whereas nobles who are
ranked fifth and lower must
adhere to the judgment of
those of higher ranking.
Oh, interesting.
Anyway, that's why someone like myself,
an heir to a sixth rank house,
is an aristocrat in name only.
In that sense, our lifestyle is really
no different from most people's.
Oh, really?
Okay,
so if your opponent
wants to get the drop on
you from above with a
high Norkian-style attack,
there's two types of strikes you've got
to be ready to defend yourself against.
They are a strike from above
or diagonally to the right.
If they do anything else, that means
they're going to switch up their footing,
so you'll still have time to block it.
Man, I'm stuffed.
Um, if it would be alright with you two?
We'd like to get your
thoughts on something.
It's about Frenika, our
roommate at the dormitory.
The elite disciple whom
she unfortunately is
forced to serve under is
a rather crude individual.
Well, over the past few days,
he's been giving her orders that
go way beyond inappropriate.
His ranking is no excuse.
If he's making her do things that violate
the school's rules, he should be reported.
That's just it.
Technically, they're not violations,
but the demands he makes of a
female student are so obscene.
You don't have to say anymore.
The problem is,
the only way to change for Nika's mentor
is to get the approval of her current one.
Can you tell us his name?
Yes.
It's second-seat elite
disciple, Umber Zizek.
I'm not surprised.
A few days ago, I had a sparring
match with Umber in the training hall.
We ended it in a draw.
In fact, he seemed pretty upset by that.
My guess is he's taking his
frustrations out on Franika.
He's doing this out of revenge?
How could he be so cruel?
I just can't understand it.
We live in a larger house
than most other civilians.
And enjoy some additional privileges,
But my father would always remind me?
that we should never take
those things for granted.
He'd say we were obliged to ensure
everyone, no matter their station,
could live a happy and peaceful life.
And if war broke out,
it's our duty to take up our
swords first and protect the weak.
And yet, because of the heartless orders!
That were issued by a noble,
Frenika couldn't help but cry
herself to sleep last night.
It's not right.
How can something like this be allowed?
Thank you.
There's a phrase in the Sacred
Tongue that comes to mind,
which, let's see, it's pronounced?
noblesse oblige, I think.
Basically,
it means whoever's got the power should
use it for the sake of the vulnerable.
Just like your father
said, it's a code of honor.
And that kind of honor is more
important than any law or custom.
There are things you just shouldn't do,
even if there's no law against them.
At the same time,
there might be stuff you should do,
even if the laws say you shouldn't.
I think I understand
what it is you're saying.
If I'm hearing you correctly, the
Taboo Index doesn't cover everything.
In cases like this one,
we have to use our own personal sense
of what's right and what's wrong.
Instead of blindly obeying laws,
we need to ask why they exist
and if they're even honorable.
That self-reflection is more
important than just blind faith.
Yep, that's exactly right.
It's super important to learn how
to act and think for yourself.
That's worth more than the best
sword or the flashiest move.
Even though Umber didn't
technically break the rules,
what he did is still 100 % wrong.
Someone's got to hold
him accountable for that.
In this case, it looks
like it's up to us, too.
Right.
We'll go and sort this out.
Well, well.
To what do we owe the pleasure
of this visit, Disciple Eugeo?
And on the evening of
our day of rest, no less.
I've come to report a troubling rumor.
Unfortunately, it concerns Disciple Zizek.
I thought I'd bring this to your attention
before it damaged his stellar reputation.
Are you mocking me?
Oh, my.
I must say, I'm surprised.
I wouldn't have expected this from you.
How thoughtful of you to be concerned
for the sake of my friend's good name.
However, I'm afraid I have no idea
what this rumor you speak of could be.
Along with the nature of these claims,
I must ask where you
acquired this information.
From Lord Zizek's page, along
with the girls who room with her.
As far as the claims are concerned,
they say Lord Zizek has been
issuing perverse orders to his page.
Franika, what are these perverse orders?
I'm not following what it is
you're getting at, Sir Eugeo.
Which of the school's regulations
has he violated specifically?
Sir,
even if something isn't
specifically forbidden here,
do you not agree there are
things an elite disciple
should never do as a
primary trainee's mentor?
Oh, I can tell this upsets you.
Now then, what exactly are you
insinuating Umber forced Fronica to do?
I couldn't say.
Well, what say you, Umber?
Do you have any idea what it is
Sir Eugeo could be referring to?
Not even the foggiest!
Try as I might, I can't
make heads nor tails of it.
It is true that I asked her to
perform some menial tasks for me.
But ever since my duel with Sir Eugeo,
which regrettably ended in a draw,
I'm a changed man and have
immersed myself fully in
my training why I've been
using muscles I did not know
I had and as a result my
body ached so badly in such
a humbled state as I was
in I had no choice but to
ask her to massage me every
night while I bathed I was
concerned she would soil
her uniform so I graciously
had her stripped down and
massage me in her undergarments
honestly I can't for the
life of me understand?
how anyone could think that perverse.
Because of your behavior,
Frenika has been beside herself.
If you continue harassing her,
I will be forced to bring
it to the attention?
of our instructors.
I hope you understand. Why you!
I appreciate the warning, Disciple Eugeo.
Do whatever you feel is right.
Don't let those jerks get to you.
I don't know how you kept so calm.
I thought I was going to lose it in there.
Lucky for them, you didn't
have your sword. Well,
at least now I'm pretty sure they're up
to something more than just being creeps.
What?
I get the feeling the reason they're going
to all this trouble is
to set a trap for you.
Really? Yeah.
Look, if you'd taken their bait
and started going off on Humber,
they could have accused you of
being disrespectful to them,
and they'd be in their
rights to punish you.
You see?
Don't worry.
If Humber doesn't stop messing
with Fronica, he'll pay.
For now, all we can do
is tell the teachers.
So stay sharp and keep your eyes open.
All right, I'll do that.
And you, Gio, if those guys say
anything to you when I'm not around,
try not to get yourself all
riled up like you did back there.
I won't, I promise.
I'll just, you know, stay cool.
Exactly.
Stay cool. Always.
Allow me to make my report.
All chores are done.
The assigned cleaning
has also been completed.
Good work, as usual.
I really appreciate it.
Oh, it's nothing on your page after all!
By the way, if you have the time, I'd
like to talk to you about something.
You don't have to stand.
Please, sit down.
Very well, if you insist.
It's about Frenika.
I had a talk with Umber
about her yesterday.
Did you really?
I doubt he wants to get into any trouble,
so I'm pretty sure he won't be
harassing her anymore. Thank goodness.
You don't know how grateful I
am, Elite Disciple Yu-Gi-Oh, sir.
Your work's done for today, so
please just call me Yu-Gi-Oh.
Anyway, there's something
I need to apologize for.
I wasn't sure of it
yesterday, but now I am.
The reason this happened
in the first place
was all because of the
duel I had with Umber.
Do you think you could set
up a meeting with her for me?
I'd like to apologize in person.
Yes, of course.
Honestly, despite what you say,
none of this is really your fault.
But I'll be more than happy to convey
your wishes to her nonetheless.
Um, could I...
Could I sit closer to you?
Uh, sure.
I've been thinking, after I
graduate from the academy,
I'll take over as head
of the Streenan family.
As is custom,
I will then have to marry a noble who
is of the same rank or possibly higher.
And it terrifies me!
What if the man who becomes my husband
turns out to be someone like Lord Zizek?
Someone who is cruel to
others and who lacks the basic
principles of honor my
father raised me to uphold.
I'm so scared.
What do I do?
Tiese.
Yujiyo, if it would be alright, I'd
like to ask another favor of you.
I have no doubt that eventually
you'll rise to the top of our class,
win the swordsmanship tournament,
and compete in the Fort
Empire Unification Tournament.
I hope to.
I mean, I am working
hard toward that goal.
And then, after that,
if you, if you rank high in
the Unification Tournament,
I heard you can be appointed as a noble.
That's what happened
with our supervisor, Ms.
Asurika.
And then, if you do decide to take a
title, do you think, would you be my...
I'm not here for the tournament.
I'm doing this to become an
Integrity Knight and find Alice.
But I can't tell her that.
It's okay.
After the tournament,
we'll talk more about this.
I'll be waiting.
And I'll work as hard as you.
I want to become strong enough.
So that I can speak up for what is right.
Just like you, Yujiya.
They are least to you.